(upbeat music)
- Hello English learners,
welcome back to another podcast
here with us at EnglishPod,
my name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And today we're bringing you another part
of our sports series, and this
time it's an advanced lesson.
- That's right, we're heading
to the mountains today
to take a skiing lesson.
- All right, so we're gonna
be learning about skiing,
a winter sport, and very
popular throughout the world.
So before we get started,
why don't we take a
look at a couple of words
in vocabulary preview?
- Very cabaret-y preview.
- All right, so we're gonna hear
these two words in our dialogue.
The first one is fresh powder.
- Fresh powder.
- Okay, so powder, we probably
know this phrase already.
- Yeah, but here we're
talking about fresh light snow.
- So fresh light snow,
snow that recently fell.
- Yep.
- Okay, so it looks like powder.
- The best kind, the
best kind for skiing on.
- Okay, the best kind.
- All right, so fresh powder.
What about our next phrase?
- Well, we're also gonna meet a
four-time giant slalom champion.
- All right, a four-time
giant slalom champion.
- Okay, so giant slalom
is a type of ski race.
- Mm-hmm, when you probably see
it on TV when they go down the hill
and they have to go through
these red or blue flags, right?
- Yep, now four-time giant slalom champion
means he won the giant slalom four times.
- Okay, so this is an
interesting way of saying
that somebody did something many times.
- Right.
- So I can say the
three-time Nobel Prize winner.
- Yes, exactly.
- Okay.
- Or the five-time Olympic gold medalist.
- Okay, perfect.
So now it's time for us
to go to the mountains
with our famous Rick Fields and Bob
Copeland, and we'll see what happens.
(upbeat music)
(audience applauding)
- Welcome, ski lovers of all ages.
My name is Rick Fields, and here with me
is the man that needs no
introduction, Bob Copeland.
- Thank you, Rick.
What a beautiful day here
in Aspen, Colorado, where the
sun is shining, and we've
got 12 inches of fresh powder.
It doesn't get much better than this.
- That's right, Bob.
But today we have a
special treat for our viewers.
We're joined here by
Inrosy, four-time giant slalom
champion, and on this
special edition of the show,
Ian is going to teach us the basics
of skiing, so let's hit the slopes.
Well, first off, let's get those boots on.
You're going to want to
make sure your boots fit snugly.
That's right.
Now snap them into your bindings,
and you're also going to want a good
pair of goggles to protect your eyes.
It's a bright day today,
so there's going to be a lot of
glare out there on the slopes.
We don't want you
hitting any of those moguls.
- Bob, since you're a beginner
skier, I might take a few spills.
It's a good idea to have a
good warm pair of dry ski gloves.
- Easy there, Rick.
Well, let's head over onto
the chairlift and test your skills.
- All right, we're up here
on the bunny hill, so, Bob.
Why don't you do a few snow plough turns?
Gnarly run, Rick, nice carving.
You've got some mad skills, that was sick.
- You want to see gnarly?
Well, see that bump over there?
I'm going to catch some major air.
- What plant?
- He lost his skis.
- He yard sale, well, thanks
for joining us here today.
I think that about does it?
Bob, meant, time for some apple gay ski?
- No, wait, man.
We'll have to grab some freshies.
- Pretty embarrassing
for Rick there, wasn't it?
- Yeah, he was a little bit cocky.
And then he ended up falling.
- Well, I think there's a
lesson in that for all of us,
but what the real lesson
is today is language.
So why don't we start
with language takeaway?
- Language takeaway.
- All right, on language takeaway today,
let's take a look at the first word.
We have some bindings.
- Bindings.
Bindings are sort of like a lock
that attaches your boot to your ski.
- Mm-hmm, so those are the bindings.
I guess it comes from the verb to bind.
- Yeah, to tie something so that it stays.
- Okay, binding.
So for example, my bindings are broken.
- Okay, and another piece of skiing
equipment and very important is goggles.
- Goggles.
- Okay, we have goggles now.
- Yep, not to be confused with Google.
- It's spelled almost the same way, huh?
- Yep, but goggles are kind of like imagine
a big pair of glasses that
you wear when you ski.
So it makes people kind of look like flies.
- Yes, yeah.
- And get these huge glasses.
- Yeah, and you'll also see safety goggles,
which you might wear if you
are a mechanic, fixing a car
or someone working with wood
or chemicals or what have you.
- Okay, so goggles
basically protect your
eyes from snow, from
the sun, from anything.
- That's right, all right.
- So moving on to our next ski word.
They said you should wear the goggles that
you don't accidentally go over the moguls.
- Okay, moguls.
- Moguls.
Okay, moguls, it sounds kind of strange.
What are these things?
- Basically these are the
bumps that are in a ski hill.
- Bumps, okay, so they're
kind of like mini little hills.
- Yep.
- And they're very
difficult to ski over, right?
- That's right, you gotta be pretty
good to handle those moguls.
- Okay.
- Now, since these
guys are beginner skiers,
they're starting out on the bunny hill.
- A bunny hill.
- The bunny hill.
- Okay, very popular among skiers.
The bunny hill is the easiest hill.
So it's where the beginners start to learn.
- Yeah, all the kids.
- All the kids are on the bunny hill.
- All right, and our final words, actually
we're gonna look at two words here
because they mean almost
exactly the same thing.
We heard the ski instructors say gnarly.
- Gnarly run.
- Yeah, gnarly.
So an interesting word,
it's spelled g-n-a-r-l-e-y.
- Okay, so, but you don't say good gnarly.
- No.
- You say gnarly.
- Yeah.
- And a related word, sick.
- Okay, now sick means to be sick, right?
- Yeah.
- No, no, no, not here.
Let's listen to some examples
to help us understand.
- Example one.
- Those were some sick dance moves.
You are amazing.
- Example two.
- Jack and I went to the beach yesterday
and served some really gnarly waves.
- Example three.
- Man, the country last night was sick.
- I can't believe we got front row seats.
- Okay, so basically gnarly and sick,
they mean that it's amazing, it was cool.
- It's awesome.
- Awesome.
So these two words are very, very informal.
It's slang.
- Yeah, and actually skier slang.
Both of these words, I think, originated
with skier snowboarders,
skateboarders, gnarly dudes.
- Gnarly dudes.
Okay, so that's all the words
we have for language takeaway,
but we have some great
phrases that we want to take
a look at before we listen
to the dialogue again.
So it's time now for fluency builder.
- Fluency builder.
All right, so Rick said that it is time to,
so Rick invited everyone to start
skiing by saying, "Let's hit the slopes.
" - Okay, so to hit the slopes.
- To hit the slopes.
- Okay, now we want to hit the slopes.
What does that mean?
- Go skiing.
- Let's go skiing.
Let's go to the mountain.
- Yep.
Change the noun slope
for something else, right?
- Yeah, you can change it for
a lot of other different nouns.
And why don't we hear some
examples of how you can do that?
- Example one.
- I really have to hit the books
and study from my exam tomorrow.
- Example two.
- I'm really tired.
I think I'm going to hit the bed now.
- Example three.
- Honey, can we hit the
supermarket on our way home?
I need to buy some milk.
- Okay, great, so great examples and
now we understand how we can use
the hit the something.
All right, what about our next phrase?
- Well, Rick warned Bob
that he might take a few spills.
- Okay, so to take a spill.
- To take a spill.
- Take a spill.
- Fall.
- To fall.
- Yep, it means like a light fall or--
- Yeah, pretty dramatic fall.
- Pretty dramatic, so yeah, fell.
- Yeah.
- So for example, instead of saying
that little girl was writing
her bike and she fell,
I can say that little girl was writing
her bike and she took a bad spill.
- Yep.
- Okay, so to take a spill, you
have to use the verb take though.
- Yes, exactly, you cannot just spill.
- Okay, you have to take a spill.
All right, what about our next phrase?
- Well, you might take a spill
when you catch some major air.
- Okay, catch some major air.
- To catch some major air.
- So, am I catching something?
How am I catching air that's impossible?
- Well, imagine if you're jumping
and your skis are catching the air.
- Okay, so I'm in the air
for a very long time, maybe?
- Yeah, when you catch some air,
basically it's like you're
flying for a couple seconds.
- So you're flying for a couple of
seconds, you're very high up in the air.
- Yep.
- Okay, to catch some air.
- Yeah, and you'll hear this phrase,
when you're not only when
you're talking about skiing,
but also maybe if you're
driving your car really fast
and it sort of jumps up in the air for
a minute, well, not a minute, a second.
That would be catching air as well.
- Okay, so to catch air.
- Mm-hmm.
- All right, so they finished
skiing, they were kind
of tired and he said,
"Well, let's call it a day.
" - To call it a day.
- Let's call it a day.
Let's go home.
- Let's go home, it's over, let's finish.
- Let's finish the day.
- Yep.
- Let's call it a day and go home.
But not before we go to our
next word to grab some freshies.
- All right, grab some freshies.
- Grab some freshies.
- Okay, freshies, what are these freshies?
- Well, remember we
talked about fresh powder?
- Mm-hmm.
- It's that.
- So it's an informal way
of saying fresh powder.
- Yeah, fresh powdery light snow.
- Okay, freshies.
- Yep, so the snow that
nobody has skied on before.
- Really good phrases and
some amazing vocabulary.
Let's listen to this dialogue one last time
and then we'll come back
and talk a little bit more
about this really fun sport.
(upbeat music)
(dramatic music)
- Welcome, ski lovers of all ages.
My name is Rick Fields and here with me
is the man that needs no
introduction, Bob Copeland.
- Thank you, Rick.
What a beautiful day
here in Aspen, Colorado.
We're the sun is shining
and we've got 12 inches
of fresh powder.
It doesn't get much better than this.
That's right, Bob.
But today we have a
special treat for our viewers.
We're joined here by Ian Rusey,
four time giant slalom champion.
And on this special edition of the show,
Ian is going to teach
us the basics of skiing.
So let's hit the slopes.
- Well, first off, let's
get those boots on.
You're going to want to
make sure your boots fit snugly.
That's right.
Now snap them into your bindings.
And you're also going to want a good
pair of goggles to protect your eyes.
It's a bright day today.
So there's going to be
a lot of glare out there
on the slopes.
We don't want you to
hang any of those moguls.
Bob, since you're a beginner
skier, it might take a few spills.
It's a good idea to have a
good warm pair of dry ski gloves.
- Easy there, Rick.
Well, let's head over onto
the chairlift and test your skills.
All right, we're up here on the bunny hill.
So, Bob, why don't you
do a few snow plow turns?
Not only run, Rick, nice carving.
You've got some mad skills.
That was sick.
You want to see gnarly.
Well, see that bump over there?
I'm going to catch some major air.
But planned.
He lost his skis.
He yard sale.
Well, thanks for joining us here today.
I think that about does it?
Bob, me and time for some apple-y ski?
No, wait, man.
We'll have to grab some freshies.
Well, we heard the
guys talk about apray ski.
And actually, this is one of
my favorite parts of skiing.
What is this?
It sounds French.
Yeah, it is.
I guess the Frenchness sort of
gives it an air of specialness, right?
But apray ski is basically the party
that you have after your finish skiing.
So, usually you would
have parties after skiing.
Right, so you finish your ski day.
You've called it a day.
You've glided down those slopes.
You head on over to
the lodge, the little cabin.
Grab a beer or two, or maybe
some hot alcoholic drink.
And kick back and relax with your friends.
Wow, so it's popular
for families to go to a
ski resort and stay there
for a couple of days.
This is when you would do
this with your friends or family.
Yeah, and you know what,
if it's with your friends,
it's going to last until
late into the night.
All right, so it sounds fun.
And next time, maybe, if
you go skiing with your friends
and you guys are speaking English
now, you can use all these great phrases
and maybe surprise your
friends if you tell them,
let's go grab some freshies
or something like that.
Yeah, you'll sound pretty,
pretty, dialed, pretty cool.
All right, so that's all we have for today.
Be sure to check out our
website EnglishPod.com.
Marco and I are always
around to answer your questions.
And, well, thanks for downloading.
Until next time, goodbye.
Bye.
(upbeat music)